

# Davey Mason Web Developer

https://daveymason.com

#### **Profile**

Natural **problem solver** and strong passion for design and performance. A **quick learner**, that's dedicated to finding the right solution.

Over two years' experience designing websites and web apps using a range of technologies, responsible for the entire stack, speed and security of over 50 websites.

I'm currently looking for a position in which I could become a **Web Development expert**.

### **Tech Stack**

HTML/CSS

Bootstrap

**JavaScript** 

- React
- > iQuery
- > Node

#### Php

- WordPress
- Laravel

MySQL

## **EDUCATION**

#### **Full-stack coding bootcamp**

*NuCamp (Online, remote)* [2021]

Revised Bootstrap and the latest standards of **Javascript**. Studied **React**, **React Native**, **Node**, **Express**, **MongoDB** & **NPM**.

#### Postgraduate Module in Software Development

*Open University. UK (Online, remote)* [2019]

Analysis, design, software construction and testing; engage with various design practices from **design patterns** to **software architectures** and **frameworks**. Course delivered in **Java**.

#### B.Sc. Digital Technology and Design

Dublin Institute of Technology

[2017 - 2018]

**User Experience** and **Concept Design**, Mobile and Web Applications, Server-Side Web Development, Web and Device Programming. Learned **HTML**, **CSS**, **Javascript**, **Php** and **MySQL** along with **Angular**, **jQuery**, **Codeignitor**, **Phonegap** & **Wordpress**.

#### **B.Sc.** Applied Physics and Instrumentation

Cork Institute of Technology

[2011 - 2014]

50% practical based with a strong emphasis on process control, quality and safety systems. Event driven programming with VB.net, as well as programming with the Siemens s7 PLC and the Emerson DeltaV automation system. Visual programming with LabView as well as various Math & Physics modules.

## RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Serve.ie - Web Developer (Remote, part-time)

[2021 - Current]

➤ Redesign, optimize & maintain serve.ie. Automate the maintenance, implement SEO, manage the hosting, domains and e-mails.

#### **DEITG I.T. Generalists - Web Developer**

[2018–2019] (18 Months)

- ➤ Designed, developed, deployed, tested, secured, maintained and updated 50+ websites and web apps.
- Designed and developed the frontend of large web apps using CakePhp & CSS.
- > Successfully improved the company's website SEO to attract new customers for all services.
- > Greatly reduced technical debt and set up automated monthly updates to keep all websites easily manageable.

### **Other Skills**

Git + GitHub
Agile (Scrum)
Web Design
UX & UI
NPM
SEO
Domains & Hosting
Google Suite
Web Performance
Web Security
PC Building
Java (Academic)
Pokemon Master

### Contact

PHONE: +13262611753

#### **GITHUB:**

https://github.com/davevmason

#### LINKEDIN:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/da vey-mason

#### **EMAIL:**

davevmason@outlook.com

### **OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Hills Kindy - Homeroom Teacher [2020 - Current]

- ➤ Homeroom teacher for an international kindergarten in my wife's hometown of TiaYuan.
- ➤ Develop STEM based lessons to teach students the basics of English, math and computer science.

## TaiYuan University of Technology - English Teacher [2019-2020]

- Created an LMS for students to continue to learn during lockdown from COVID-19.
- ➤ Delivered online classes on a weekly basis to help students improve their English listening skills.

#### **DEITG I.T. Generalists - Web Developer**

[2018–2019] (Previous page)

### B.Sc. Digital Technology and Design - Student Dublin Institute of Technology

[2016-2018] (Previous page)

## Various Schools in China - Teacher [2014-2016]

- ➤ Worked with an agency to teach in primary and secondary schools in various locations in China.
- ➤ Subjects included English, Math & Science to various grades.
- > Some roles included curriculum design & implementation.

# Cork Institute of Technology - Student Support [2013-2014]

- ➤ Provided a range of community building services including an information desk & weekly institute newsletter.
- > Designed posters and newsletters using Photoshop & MS Office.
- > Organized charity events for daffodil day and assisted with Students Union charity events.
- > Focal point of contact for international students solving all sorts of problems they had living and studying in Ireland.